[upbeat music]
- Well, boys, enjoy your last few minutes before we're stuck with the babysitter.
- 好了，孩子们，享受你们最后的几分钟吧，我们就要和保姆一起被困在这里了。
- Why do Mom and Dad think we still need the babysitter?
- 为什么妈妈和爸爸还觉得我们需要保姆？
- Yeah, we're responsible.
- 是啊，我们很负责任。
We're, like, the most responsible kids in the world.
我们是世界上最负责任的孩子。
[whimpers]
- Guys, I know we're bummed, but whoever's whining, please knock it off.
- 伙计们，我知道我们很沮丧，但谁在抱怨，请停下来。
You sound like a dog who needs to go to the bathroom.
你听起来像只需要上厕所的狗。
- Hey, kids.
- 嘿，孩子们。
Guess who's almost here.
猜猜谁快到了。
- The babysitter.
- 保姆。
all: The babysitter.
大家都说：保姆。
- I'm so excited we are finally getting a date night
- 我太兴奋了，我们终于能有个约会夜
at Chateau Mamouche.
在Chateau Mamouche。
- It's pronounced "ma-mouch,"
- 它的发音是“ma-mouch”，
as in "get that food in ma mouch."
就像“把食物放进我的嘴里”。
- No, no, no!
- 不，不，不！
- No, it's pronounced, "Non, non, non."
- 不，它的发音是，“Non, non, non.”
- No, the babysitter just cancelled.
- 不，保姆刚刚取消了。
all: The babysitter!
大家：保姆！
- The babysitter.
保姆。
- Now we'll never find a sitter so last-minute.
现在我们永远找不到这么临时的一个看护了。
Well, there goes date night.
好吧，约会之夜泡汤了。
- Unless...
除非...
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
哦，不，不，不，不，不。
You are not staying home alone.
你不能一个人留在家里。
You kids ask us this every time.
你们孩子每次都问我们这个。
Your mother never goes for it, and she's not going to go for it now.
你妈妈从来不同意，现在也不会同意的。
- I might go for it now. - You're going for it now?
我现在可能会同意。
all: Yes!
你们同意了？
- Well, the kids are getting older, and, I don't know,
好吧，孩子们都长大了，我不知道，
maybe it's time we give them a shot at this.
也许现在是时候让他们尝试一下了。
- But you're not worried?
但你不会担心吗？
- No.
不会。
- Well, someone has to worry, and usually it's you.
嗯，总得有人担心，通常是你。
But if you're not worried, that means I have to be worried.
但如果你不担心，那就意味着我得担心了。
Aren't you worried about that?
你难道不担心吗？
- Not really.
不太担心。
- But they can't even take care of Squishy.
但他们甚至照顾不好Squishy。
- Yeah, we can.
是的，我们可以。
Ricky, it's your turn to take Squish out.
瑞奇，轮到你带Squish出去了。
- No, it's not. - I did it last time.
- 不，不是我。 - 我上次已经做过了。
- It's not my turn. - Dawn, it's your turn.
- 不是我的轮次。 - 黎明，轮到你了。
[kids arguing]
[孩子们争吵]
- See?
- 看吧？
This kind of arguing is why you can't be left alone.
这种争吵就是为什么不能让你们单独待着的原因。
I swear it's been going on since before you were born.
我发誓这种情况从你出生前就开始了。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- [moans] It's so good.
- [呻吟] 太好吃了。
Give me some of this right here.
给我来点这里的。
- No, that's mine.
不，那是我的。
- Oh, sweet quesadilla. I love you.
哦，美味的玉米饼。我爱你。
- Honey?
亲爱的？
Honey, you need to slow down.
亲爱的，你需要慢下来。
That's the whole left side of the menu.
那可是菜单上一半的东西。
- I am growing four humans in my body cell by cell!
我正在一个细胞一个细胞地孕育四个人类！
Do you not see what they're doing inside of me?
你难道没看到他们在我体内做什么吗？
- They're just kicking.
他们只是在踢腿。
It's adorable.
真可爱。
Goo-goo-ga-ga.
咕咕嘎嘎。
- No, it is not goo-goo-ga-ga.
不，这不仅仅是‘咕咕嘎嘎’。
It's like a steel cage match in here.
这里简直就像是一场钢铁牢笼赛。
[grunting]
[哼哼]
- Take it back! Take it back!
收回你的话！收回你的话！
- Never!
绝不！
- Don't tell me what to do!
别命令我！
- Goo-goo-ga-ga.
‘咕咕嘎嘎’。
- What is that horrible noise?
那是什么可怕的声音？
- Goo-goo-ga-ga. - Make it stop!
‘咕咕嘎嘎’。 - 让它停下来！
- Maybe this will work!
也许这会有用！
- Ow.
哎哟。
Making it worse!
变得更糟了！
[screams]
[尖叫]
- And you're still arguing like that,
而你们还在那样争吵，
which means you're not responsible enough
这意味着你们还不够成熟
to stay home alone.
不能独自待在家里。
- Well, then what if you put one of us in charge?
那么，如果你让我们中的一个人负责呢？
That way, we'll have one clear leader,
这样，我们就会有一个明确的领导者，
which means no arguing and no problems.
这意味着没有争吵，也没有问题。
- Oh, and I bet you have an opinion of who that person should be.
哦，我敢打赌你对那个人选有意见。
- I do. You.
我有。就是你。
- [gasps] Don't let my gasp fool you.
- [倒吸气] 别让我的倒吸气骗了你。
I knew this moment would come.
我就知道这一刻会来。
I even have a presentation titled
我甚至准备了一个演讲稿，题目是
"Ricky Harper's Guide
"瑞奇·哈珀负责任地独自在家指南"
to Responsibly Staying Home Alone."
。
- See, honey? There is nothing to worry about.
- 看吧，亲爱的？没什么好担心的。
- Have you met our children, Anne?
- 安妮，你了解我们的孩子吗？
- Okay, look. Why don't we just go to El Pepper Pot?
- 好吧，听着。我们为什么不去艾尔辣椒罐餐厅呢？
That way, we can still have our date night,
这样我们还能继续我们的约会夜，
but we'll be close in case anything happens.
但我们会很近，以防万一发生什么事。
[dog barks]
[狗叫]
[laughs] See?
[笑] 看吧？
Even Squishy approves.
连Squishy都同意了。
He loves it when we bring him his favorite nacho balls.
他最喜欢我们带他去吃他最爱的玉米球。
- It's true. He does.
- 确实，他喜欢。
Then it's settled.
那就这么定了。
You take Squishy to El Pepper Pot,
你带Squishy去El Pepper Pot，
and I'll stay here with the kids.
我留在这里陪孩子们。
- Or you can take me to El Pepper Pot,
- 或者你可以带我去El Pepper Pot，
and we can stay married.
这样我们就可以继续保持婚姻关系。
- All right, kids. You're on your own.
- 好了，孩子们，你们自己照顾自己吧。
all: Yes!
太好了！
- Make good choices, and call us if you need anything.
- 做出明智的选择，有需要就给我们打电话。
- Don't burn the house down-- - Don't look back!
- 别把房子烧了—— - 别回头看！
all: Yes!
太好了！
- First time alone in the house.
- 第一次独自在家。
What do we do first, Captain?
我们首先做什么，队长？
- I'll grab my presentation.
- 我去拿我的演示文稿。
You guys should get some snacks.
你们应该去拿些零食。
It's got quite the running time.
这电影时长可不短。
Dah!
啊！
- Oh, Ricky.
- 哦，里基。
So cute, so innocent. So not in charge.
真可爱，真天真。真不是负责的。
- What?
- 什么？
- Look at me.
- 看我。
I'm the captain now.
我现在是队长了。
both: Uh-oh.
两人：哎呀。
[whimpers]
[呜咽声]
[upbeat music]
[欢快音乐]
- ♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na ♪ - ♪ Hey! ♪
♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪ ♪ 嘿！ ♪
- ♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na ♪
♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
[whistling]
[吹口哨]
♪ ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
♪ 一二三四！ ♪
♪ ♪
- ♪ Na na na na na na ♪
♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
♪ Na na na na na na ♪ - ♪ Hey! ♪
♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪ ♪ 嘿！ ♪
- ♪ One, two ♪ - ♪ Na na na na na na ♪
♪ 一二 ♪ ♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
♪ 一二三四！ ♪
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- What do you mean, you're the captain now?
- 你什么意思，你现在成了队长了？
You made me the captain. I'm the captain.
你让我当队长的。我现在是队长。
You guys heard her.
你们都听到了。
- I don't really listen much.
- 我其实没怎么听。
- Well, she did.
- 嗯，她确实说了。
Somebody salute me!
有人向我致敬！
- I was only saying that to get Mom and Dad out of the house.
- 我那么说只是为了让爸妈离开房子。
Now, if anyone is in charge, it's me.
现在，如果有人负责，那就是我。
After all, I've been the captain since the day we were born.
毕竟，从我们出生的那天起，我就是队长了。
- Looks pretty scary. What do you think is out there?
- 看起来挺吓人的。你觉得外面有什么？
- I don't know, because I'm not the leader.
- 我不知道，因为我不是领导者。
And I'm not smart.
而且我也不聪明。
- Let's ask the captain.
- 我们去问船长吧。
- It has been a long voyage, womb mateys.
- 这是一段漫长的航程，子宫伙伴们。
But it is time to abandon this mother ship for dry land.
但现在是时候离开这艘母舰，前往陆地了。
- But I'm scared, Captain.
- 但我害怕，船长。
- We must be brave, little one,
- 我们必须勇敢，小家伙，
and face whatever is out there.
面对外面的一切。
Now wait four seconds and then follow me out into the unknown.
现在等四秒钟，然后跟着我进入未知。
Let's bounce!
我们出发吧！
- What are seconds?
- 什么是秒？
You can't possibly remember any of that.
你不可能记得任何那些。
- You have your memories. I have mine.
- 你有你的记忆。我有我的。
Now, my first decision is for us to...
现在，我的第一个决定是让我们...
watch TV.
看电视。
- Where does she come up with this stuff?
- 她从哪儿想出这些的？
- Permission to come aboard, Captain?
- 请求登船，船长？
- Permission granted.
- 允许登船。
- Hey, Captain, the dog needs to go outside and drop an anchor.
- 嘿，船长，狗需要出去放下锚。
- My second decision is to unlock the doggy door
我的第二个决定是打开狗门，
so we don't have to spend the next 20 minutes walking him.
这样我们就不必花接下来的20分钟遛他了。
[snaps fingers]
- [sighs]
I'm pretty sure Mom and Dad keep that locked for a reason.
我很确定爸妈锁着它是有原因的。
- Come on, boy!
来吧，小子！
Come on!
来吧！
Relax. Now he's free to do his business wherever he wants.
放松。现在他可以自由地在他想的地方解决。
- Wow, he's really digging back there.
哇，他真的在那边挖得很起劲。
- I've never seen him dig so fast.
我从没见过他挖得这么快。
- See? Look how happy he is.
看？看他多开心。
Look at his little paws go.
看他的小爪子动得多快。
[dog barks]
（狗叫声）
- And there he goes!
他跑出去了！
Right under the fence.
直接从栅栏下面钻出去了。
- And out of the yard.
然后就跑出后院了。
- Run! - Wait!
快跑！
I'm the captain now.
等等！
I say when we run.
我现在是队长了。
Now we run!
我说什么时候跑就什么时候跑。现在我们跑！
[upbeat music]
- ♪ La, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
♪啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦♪
- Isn't this great, Tom?
这不是很棒吗，汤姆？
[chuckles]
（轻笑）
Do you remember when I was pregnant
你还记得我怀孕的时候吗
and I ordered, like, this whole side of the menu?
我点了一整面的菜单？
- Yeah, that was crazy.
是啊，那真是疯狂。
Those are just appetizers.
那些只是开胃菜。
Hi.
你好。
I'd like to order this whole side of the menu.
我想点这一整面的菜单。
- Tom, you just ordered nine entrées.
- 汤姆，你刚点了九道主菜。
- Oh. Ooh, right.
- 哦。哦，对。
And whatever the lady wants.
还有这位女士想要的任何东西。
- Uh, the lady is going to need a minute.
- 呃，这位女士需要一点时间。
- Yeah, but you can get rolling on mine.
- 是的，但你可以开始准备我的。
- Honey, why are you ordering so much?
- 亲爱的，你为什么要点这么多？
- It was fine when you did it.
- 你这么做的时候也没问题啊。
- Yeah, but when I did it, I had a belly full of kids.
- 是啊，但我那时候肚子里装满了孩子。
- Yeah, well, I have a house full of kids, Anne.
- 是啊，我家里也满是孩子，安妮。
And who knows what they're up to?
谁知道他们在搞什么鬼？
[crunching]
咔嚓咔嚓
We're going to need a bigger basket!
我们需要一个更大的篮子！
- There he is!
- 他在那儿！
- And there he goes.
- 他走了。
- And there they are!
- 他们在那儿！
- Aye, aye, aye!
- 哎呀，哎呀，哎呀！
- You, you, you what?
- 你，你，你什么？
- No, aye, aye, aye, what are we going to do?
- 不，哎呀，哎呀，哎呀，我们该怎么办？
- Oh, first Dawn's going to look at me.
- 哦，首先Dawn会看着我。
- For what? - This.
- 为什么？ - 这个。
I'm the captain now.
我现在是船长了。
- Aye, aye, aye. I can't believe I looked.
哎呀，哎呀，哎呀。我不敢相信我看了。
- You may have been born first,
你可能先出生，
but I've always been calling the shots.
但我一直都在发号施令。
- I don't know about you guys, but I'm scared.
我不知道你们怎么想，但我很害怕。
- Me too.
我也是。
If only there was a much more intelligent,
如果有一个更聪明、
well-read leader to help guide us.
博学的领导者来帮助我们该多好。
- Yes, if only.
是啊，如果真是那样就好了。
I've just finished reading "Good Night, Womb,"
我刚读完《晚安，子宫》，
and I have a theory about the outside world.
而且我对外界有一个理论。
Dawn...
黎明...
Take a walk with me.
和我一起散个步吧。
So how do you think it's been going in here?
那么你觉得这里的情况怎么样？
Can you believe it's already been nine months?
你能相信已经九个月了吗？
- I know. The time just flies.
我知道。时间过得真快。
- So do you. - [screams]
你也一样。
- What was that?
那是什么？
- I needed to test my theory.
我需要验证我的理论。
And I'm correct.
我是对的。
She didn't come back, so it must be nice out there.
她没有回来，所以外面一定很美。
Four, three, two! Let's roll!
四，三，二！我们走！
See? I've always been the man with a plan.
看吧？我一直是那个有计划的人。
Now, we need to go in there and get Squishy
现在，我们需要进去把Squishy带出来
before Mom and Dad see him.
在爸爸妈妈看到他之前。
- But how are we going to do that without them seeing us?
- 但我们怎么能在不被他们看到的情况下做到呢？
["Mexican Hat Dance"]
[墨西哥帽舞]
♪ ♪
- You brought a fake mustache?
- 你带了假胡子？
- You didn't?
- 你没有？
- Anybody see Squishy?
有人看到Squishy了吗？
- No, but look at all that food on Mom and Dad's table.
没有，但看看爸爸妈妈桌子上的那些食物。
- Were they meeting friends?
他们在见朋友吗？
Because that's a lot of nacho balls.
因为那有很多玉米片球。
- Squishy's heading right for 'em.
Squishy正朝它们走去。
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
♪ ♪
- Oh, look, honey.
哦，看，亲爱的。
They must be having a date night too.
他们一定也在过约会之夜。
[giggles] It's so romantic.
[咯咯笑] 太浪漫了。
Here, hold my hand.
这里，握住我的手。
Honey, this is out of control.
亲爱的，这太失控了。
- No, it is perfectly in control.
- 不，这完全在控制之中。
May I please have my hand back?
请问我可以拿回我的手吗？
I want to eat it.
我想吃掉它。
- Tom, relax.
- 汤姆，放松。
Trust me, the kids are home safe.
相信我，孩子们都安全在家。
- Excuse me, waiter?
- 对不起，服务员？
Can we get some more chips, please?
请给我们再来点薯片，好吗？
- [in deep voice] Si.
- [用深沉的声音] 是的。
- Wait a second.
Something's wrong here.
And some table-side guac.
- Si. - Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Don?
Don's another word for "sir" in Spanish.
Don, my good man.
We would also like a fajita platter, please.
- Si.
- Merci.
- Squishy's too close to Mom and Dad.
- Squishy离爸爸妈妈太近了。
What are we going to do?
我们该怎么办？
- You're going to let the captain take care of it.
- 你要让队长来处理这件事。
Squishy, Squishy.
Squishy, Squishy。
I got your favorite, nacho balls.
我给你带来了你最喜欢的，玉米片球。
See? Here he comes.
看？他来了。
- There he goes again.
- 他又来了。
- Run! - No fair!
- 跑！ - 不公平！
You got to say "run" when you were captain!
你当队长的时候得说“跑”！
♪
- This is hopeless.
- 这没希望了。
We've looked everywhere.
- 我们到处都找过了。
- Great job, el capitan.
- 干得好，队长。
Now Squishy's really lost.
- 现在Squishy真的丢了。
- Me? You left the doggy door open.
- 我？你没关狗门。
- Hey, look.
- 嘿，看。
Squishy's inside.
- Squishy在里面。
- Because I left the doggy door open.
- 因为我没关狗门。
- It looks like Squishy has company.
- 看来Squishy有伴了。
- Because you left the doggy door open.
- 因为你没关狗门。
- Those nacho balls are every dog's favorite.
那些玉米片球是每只狗的最爱。
- We've got to get them out of our house.
我们得把它们从我们家弄出去。
- Uh-oh.
哎呀。
We're locked out.
我们被锁在外面了。
- I wish there was a way to pick this lock.
我希望有办法打开这个锁。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
Dawn, let me have one of your hairpins.
Dawn，给我一个你的发夹。
- Oh, good idea!
哦，好主意！
- Now I can get a better look.
现在我可以看得更清楚了。
Nope. No way to pick it.
不行。没办法打开。
- No, no, no! - No!
- 不，不，不！ - 不行！
- Really?
- 真的吗？
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- ♪ La, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la, la ♪
- ♪啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦♪
- We checked the front door and the garage door.
- 我们检查了前门和车库门。
- Everything's locked.
- 所有的门都锁着。
- We got to get in there before they destroy the house.
- 我们得在他们破坏房子之前进去。
- Okay, if my calculations are correct,
- 好的，如果我的计算没错，
we can jump off that tree, onto the hammock,
我们可以从那棵树上跳到吊床上，
which will catapult us onto the roof and then down the chimney.
然后弹射到屋顶再从烟囱滑下来。
- And right into the hospital.
- 然后直接进医院。
- Sorry, Ricky,
- 对不起，Ricky，
but you're not the captain of this ship anymore.
- 但你不再是这艘船的船长了。
- Neither of you are.
- 你们俩都不是。
- You think you could do better?
- 你以为你能做得更好？
- Well, it would definitely be a lot safer.
- 嗯，那肯定会安全得多。
After all, according to my best pre-birth memory...
- 毕竟，根据我出生前最好的记忆……
- I'm going first.
- 我先上。
- No, I'm going first.
- 不，我先上。
- Trust me, they're going to want to see this first.
- 相信我，他们会想先看到这个。
- Who's "they"? What are you talking about?
- “他们”是谁？你在说什么？
[whistle blows]
[哨声响起]
- What are you doing?
- 你在干什么？
- Whoa, he has a whistle.
- 哇，他有哨子。
He must be in charge. - It's true.
他一定是负责人。 - 没错。
Whistles traditionally indicate some type of authority.
哨子传统上表示某种权威。
- We should probably listen to him.
- 我们或许应该听他的。
- If you all fall down together, you'll get stuck.
- 如果你们一起摔倒，你们会卡住。
So line up in an orderly fashion!
所以请有序地排队！
Wait for my whistle...
等我的哨声...
[blows whistle] Then go.
[吹哨] 然后出发。
[blows whistle] Go!
[吹哨] 走！
[blows whistle] Go--
[吹哨] 走--
Oh, wait. That's me.
哦，等等。那是我。
Whee.
哇。
- There's no way you had a whistle in there.
- 你不可能在那里藏了个哨子。
- Well, there's no way you had a book,
- 好吧，你也不可能藏了本书，
but if you did have a book,
但如果你的确有本书，
the name of that book would be "I'm the Captain Now."
那本书的名字会是《我现在是船长了》。
- Fine, Captain.
- 好吧，船长。
How do we get in the house?
我们怎么进屋？
- Easy, through the doggy door!
- 简单，通过狗门！
- We probably shouldn't have gone all at once.
- 我们可能不该一下子全进去。
- This wouldn't have happened if I'd had my whistle.
- 如果我有我的哨子，这事儿就不会发生了。
- This couldn't get any worse.
- 这不能再糟了。
[dog panting]
[狗喘气]
all: No, no, no, no, no, no!
大家：不，不，不，不，不，不！
Eww!
呃！
Ricky, Dicky, and Dawn: You're out!
Ricky, Dicky, 和 Dawn: 你出局了！
- That seems fair.
- 这看起来很公平。
[upbeat music]
- ♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
- ♪ 哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦，哦 ♪
- Tom, that is the Papa Grande. It's an eight-pound burrito.
- Tom, 那是Papa Grande。一个八磅重的玉米卷饼。
You need to go slow.
你需要慢慢来。
- Too late!
- 太晚了！
The Papa Grande is in Papa Tom.
Papa Grande 进了 Papa Tom。
- Well, you're going to be popping buttons
- 好吧，如果你不停下这些吃的东西，
if you don't stop all this eating.
你就要开始崩扣子了。
I can't believe you don't have a stomachache by now.
我真不敢相信你现在还没胃疼。
- Honey, when you've got a stomach of steel like I--
- 亲爱的，当你有个像我这样的钢铁胃--
[stomach gurgling]
[肚子咕噜声]
That's new.
这倒是新情况。
- Are you okay?
- 你还好吗？
- Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine. It's passed.
- 是的，我没事，已经过去了。
- Okay. - Whoo! [laughs]
- 好的。- 哇！[笑]
So you want to split a Mexican chonga--
所以你想和我分享一个墨西哥卷饼--
[stomach gurgling] Oh! Uh-oh!
[肚子咕噜声] 哦！哎呀！
Ooh! Ooh!
哦！哦！
- Okay, honey, just breathe through it, okay?
好的，亲爱的，深呼吸，好吗？
[rhythmic breathing]
[有节奏的呼吸]
- Okay. Okay, I'm fine.
好的，我没事。
- Great! - I'm fine.
太好了！我没事。
You know, I'm not even worried about the kids anymore.
你知道吗，我现在甚至不担心孩子们了。
You know, we can still enjoy a nice, romantic...
我们可以继续享受一个美好的，浪漫的……
[stomach gurgling] Evening! Ow!
[肚子咕噜声] 晚上！哎哟！
La, la, la, la, la, la, la.
啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦，啦。
Oh.
哦。
Oh, wow. Oh, wow.
哦，哇。哦，哇。
Oh, wow. They're coming faster now, Anne.
哦，哇。它们现在来得更快了，Anne。
- Okay-- - Oh! [babbles]
好的——哦！[喃喃自语]
Oh! Oh, wow!
哦！哇！
It's like that burrito's kicking in there.
好像那个玉米卷正在发挥作用。
- Okay! Excuse me! Excuse me!
好的！对不起！对不起！
Can we get the check, please?
请给我们结账，好吗？
- Oh, oh! - Oh, no. I'm so sorry!
哦，哦！哦，不。我很抱歉！
- My water broke, Anne!
我的羊水破了，Anne！
- Let's get you home.
我们回家吧。
- So embarrassing! - Come on.
太尴尬了！来吧。
You got this. - [grunting]
你能行的。
- Okay, okay.
好了，好了。
I am so sorry. My husband is with burrito.
非常抱歉。我丈夫和墨西哥卷饼在一起。
- You let me do this to myself! - It's okay.
你让我这么做的！
- Don't look at me! I'm hideous!
没关系。
[upbeat music]
别看我！我太丑了！
- What are we going to do now?
我们现在该怎么办？
- If Mom and Dad come home to find us like this,
如果爸爸妈妈回家看到我们这样，
they'll never let us stay home alone again!
他们再也不会让我们单独待在家里了！
- Wait, who's been the captain?
等等，谁是队长？
You've been the captain.
你一直是队长。
Hey, I'm the captain now.
嘿，我现在是队长了。
Just like I was when we were womb-ies.
就像我们在妈妈肚子里时一样。
- I'm scared. - Me too.
- 我害怕。 - 我也是。
I don't know what to do.
我不知道该怎么办。
- If only we had a calm, cool leader
- 要是我们有一个冷静、酷炫的领导者就好了，
with sweet hair and smooth dance moves.
有着甜美的发型和流畅的舞步。
- [beatboxing]
- [节奏口技]
- Like that guy!
- 就像那家伙！
- Wow, he's cool!
- 哇，他真酷！
- And calm!
- 而且很冷静！
- For some reason, I trust him.
- 不知为何，我信任他。
- Here's what we got to do.
- 我们得这么做。
Everybody just relax, clear your mind,
大家放松，清空思绪，
and we're going to dance our way out of here.
我们要用舞蹈的方式离开这里。
Ladies first.
女士优先。
- What's a lady?
- 女士是什么？
- I don't know, but I have a feeling
- 我不知道，但我有种感觉
they're going to love me.
他们会爱上我的。
Now let's dance.
现在让我们跳舞。
all: ♪ Goo-goo-goo-goo-ga-ga! ♪
♪ Goo-goo-goo-goo-ga-ga! ♪
[screaming]
[尖叫]
So that's all we've got to do.
所以我们只需要这样做。
Just clear your mind, and dance like no one's watching.
只要清空你的思绪，像没人看一样跳舞。
[beatboxing]
[打节奏]
- How is this going to help?
- 这怎么能帮到我们？
- It's working. I moved a little.
- 有效果。我稍微动了一下。
- The dog slobber is making us slippery!
狗的口水让我们滑溜溜的！
- But there's not enough of it!
但还不够多！
- Just keep dancing.
继续跳舞。
[beatboxing]
[口技]
- Would you stop ooncing?
你能别跳了吗？
Your breath smells like nacho balls.
你的呼吸闻起来像玉米片球。
- That's it! Here, boy!
就是这样！来，小子！
You want a treat?
想要奖励吗？
[belches]
[打嗝]
- Ugh.
呃。
- Eww! - Gross! - Oh so slimy. - I'm okay with it.
- 哎呀！ - 恶心！ - 哦，太黏滑了。 - 我还能接受。
- Now what?
- 现在怎么办？
- We oonce our way out of here.
- 我们用oonce舞步出去。
all: ♪ Oonce, oonce, oonce, oonce, oonce, oonce ♪
♪ Oonce, oonce, oonce, oonce, oonce, oonce ♪
- It worked!
- 奏效了！
[all cheer]
[众人欢呼]
Now back in.
现在再进去。
- Okay. - Not all at once!
- 好的。 - 不要一下子全进去！
- Come on, guys. We have to hurry.
- 快点，伙计们。我们得抓紧时间。
Mom and Dad will be home any minute,
爸爸妈妈随时会回家，
and we've got to get this kitchen cleaned up.
而且我们必须把这个厨房打扫干净。
- And the living room.
- 还有客厅。
[dogs barking]
[狗叫声]
- Why is everybody looking at me?
- 为什么大家都看着我？
- Because your plan worked.
- 因为你的计划成功了。
- You're the captain now.
- 你现在是大哥了。
- Aye, aye, Captain.
- 是的，大哥。
- You, you captain?
- 你，你是大哥？
No, me, me captain.
不，我，我是大哥。
- We're really going to let this guy be captain?
- 我们真的要让这家伙当大哥吗？
- No, I got this.
不，我来处理。
You're on trash cleanup.
你负责清理垃圾。
You're on poop patrol.
你负责巡查便便。
You vacuum--
你用吸尘器——
and not like how Dad vacuums,
不是像爸爸那样吸，
like Mom.
而是像妈妈那样。
- And what are you going to do?
那你打算做什么？
- I'm going to get these dogs out of the house.
我要把这些狗弄出房子。
Here, boys.
来，孩子们。
[belches]
（打嗝声）
[upbeat music]
♪ ♪
- Okay.
- 好的。
The house is clean.
房子已经打扫干净了。
Dicky!
迪基！
- I tried to get them out, but for some weird reason,
- 我试着把它们赶出去，但出于某种奇怪的原因，
they keep following me back in.
它们一直跟着我回来。
- Um, what's in your pocket?
- 呃，你口袋里是什么？
- Oh, I forgot.
- 哦，我忘了。
I snagged a nacho ball from the restaurant.
我从餐厅拿了一个玉米片球。
Now, what could these dogs want?
现在，这些狗想要什么呢？
- [sighs]
You want it, boys? You want it?
你们想要吗，孩子们？你们想要吗？
You want the ball? Go get it.
你们想要那个球吗？去拿吧。
Go get it! Go get it!
去拿吧！去拿吧！
Go on. Go get it.
去吧。去拿吧。
Uh-uh.
呃，不行。
Not you.
不是你。
- Come on. We're almost there.
快点。我们快到了。
- Oh, so much food!
哦，这么多食物！
- Mom and Dad are here!
- 爸爸妈妈来了！
- Oh, come on.
- 哎呀，得了吧。
- Honey, let's get you into the kitchen.
- 亲爱的，我们进厨房吧。
Some antacids will help.
吃点抗酸药会好些。
- [groans] You're never going to want to go
- [呻吟] 你以后再也不会想和我一起过约会夜了，对吗？
on another date night with me again, are you?
- 汤姆，你现在不想听我回答这个问题。
- You don't want me to answer that right now, Tom.
- 总之，当父母信任我们独自在家时，责任感至关重要,
- To summarize, when parents trust us to be left home alone,
因为这不仅是一种特权，更是一种荣誉。
responsibility is paramount,
当父母信任我们独自在家时，责任感至关重要,
for this is not only a privilege but an honor.
因为这不仅是一种特权，更是一种荣誉。
Thank you.
谢谢。
[applause]
掌声
- Look, Tom.
听着，汤姆。
Our responsible, well-behaved children
我们负责任、行为端正的孩子们
are perfectly safe.
非常安全。
- That's right.
没错。
You left, and we didn't even argue once.
你走了，我们甚至一次都没争吵。
- Aw.
哎呀。
See, Tom?
看到了吧，汤姆？
Oh, Squishy, we brought you home your favorite nacho balls.
哦，小家伙，我们给你带了你最喜欢的玉米片球。
[barking]
[吠叫]
- Uh, what happened to your stomach, Dad?
- 爸，你的肚子怎么了？
- You look pregmint.
- 你看起来像是怀孕了。
- Oh, your father ate a little too much
- 哦，你爸爸吃得有点多
because he was worried about you guys.
因为他担心你们。
I'm guessing he feels a little silly now, huh?
我猜他现在感觉有点傻，对吧？
- I'm feeling a little something.
- 我确实感觉有点什么。
I'm going to get some tea.
我去喝点茶。
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
- So how was date night?
- 那么约会之夜怎么样？
- Why is there a dog in our cupboard?
为什么我们橱柜里有只狗？
- Uh, there's a logical explanation for that.
呃，这有个合理的解释。
- Yeah, it's not like we had some big dog party in here.
是啊，又不像是我们在里面办了个大型狗狗派对。
[nervous laughter]
（紧张的笑声）
- What?
什么？
[dogs barking]
（狗叫声）
So you did have a big dog party.
所以你们真的办了个大型狗狗派对。
[barking]
（狗叫声）
A very big dog party.
一个非常大的狗狗派对。
- Okay, technically, it was Squishy's party.
好吧，严格来说，那是Squishy的派对。
- After he ran out the doggy door, dug under the fence,
- 他从狗门跑出去，挖洞穿过了栅栏，
and went to El Pepper Pot, they followed him back here.
然后去了El Pepper Pot，他们跟着他回到了这里。
Ricky, Nicky, and Dawn: Dicky!
Ricky, Nicky, 和 Dawn: Dicky!
- Squishy was in El Pepper Pot?
- Squishy在El Pepper Pot？
- Just until we got him out.
- 只是直到我们把他带出来。
Ricky, Nicky, and Dawn: Dicky!
Ricky, Nicky, 和 Dawn: Dicky!
- You were in El Pepper Pot?
- 你在El Pepper Pot？
- Well, I guess I didn't do this to myself for no reason.
- 嗯，我想我不会无缘无故这么做。
Oh, who's my little cup of tea?
哦，谁是我的小甜心？
Yes, you are.
是的，你是。
- So any chance this will affect
- 那这次事件会影响
you letting us stay home alone again?
你让我们再次独自在家吗？
- Hmm, well, there is a dog licking guac off my shoe,
- 嗯，有只狗正在舔我鞋上的鳄梨酱，
so I'm thinking we're going back to the babysitter.
所以我想我们得回到保姆那儿了。
all: The babysitter.
保姆。
- Ahh, the babysitter.
- 啊，保姆。
- Please get the dogs out of the house.
- 请把狗弄出房子。
- Take care of Chamomile for me.
- 帮我照顾好甘菊。
- Don't worry. Captain Dicky has a plan.
- 别担心。队长迪基有个计划。
- No.
- 不。
Every time one of us tries to be the leader,
每次我们中有人试图成为领导者，
it just makes things worse.
事情只会变得更糟。
- She's right.
- 她说得对。
- Yeah, we always work best as a team.
- 是的，我们作为一个团队总是表现最好。
- So let's do this.
- 那我们就这么做吧。
Come on, pups.
来吧，小狗们。
- Come on, boy. Come on.
- 来吧，男孩。来吧。
- Me first. - Ow.
- 我先来。 - 哎哟。
- Me. - No, me!
- 我。 - 不，我！
[all yelling]
[所有人都在喊]
- Guys, stop.
伙计们，停下。
I may not be the captain, but we know what we have to do.
我可能不是队长，但我们都知道我们必须做什么。
all: ♪ Oonce, oonce, oonce, oonce, oonce, oonce ♪
♪ Oonce, oonce, oonce, oonce, oonce, oonce ♪
[whistling]
[口哨声]
♪ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
- ♪ 耶！ ♪